[My lord, Her Highness]
郎君
[has granted you a marriage.]
太皇太后赐婚
[Should we start making preparations?]
府里可需准备
Uncle Zhong,
忠叔
you don't need to lift a finger.
哪里轮得到您出马
With me, the guardian, here,
有我这个门神在
there's no way she'll get into the manor.
还能让她进得了府
[Again with that]
又是你那个
head-throwing and dart-piercing divine
扔人头扎飞镖
[technique of yours to scare people?]
仙人大法吓唬人啊
[This was granted by Her Highness herself.]
这次可是太皇太后赐婚
Maybe it's...
会不会
[So what?]
御赐又怎么样
[We'll do as we always did.]
老规矩
[We'll scare her away.]
吓跑她
[Prime Minister Zhang,]
张相
[maybe...]
这
[Enough.]
好了
[Say no more.]
不要再说了
[Just do as I said.]
就照我说的办
Yan the Erudite,
颜博士
you're a bright man.
你是个明白人
I believe you surely
必然不会辜负
will live up to my trust in you.
老夫对你的信赖
Prime Minister Zhang, rest assured.
张相放心
Close the door.
关门
[My lord,]
夫君
what was it for that
张相亲自前来
Chancellor Zhang had come here himself.
所为何事呀
Shen Du has always refrained
这沈渡在朝堂之中
from getting involved in court factions,
素来不参与派系
especially in the conflict between Prince Xian and Prince Ying.
尤其是贤王和英王之争
He has always remained neutral.
一向中立
[Prime Minister Zhang is Prince Xian's]
张相乃是贤王智囊
[strategist. Choosing Caiwei this time]
此次选中三娘
surely isn't just because of her talent.
定然不会只是因为才情
He wants to use Caiwei as an informant?
他想让采薇去当眼线
Keep your voice down.
小点声
[No.]
不行
Then Caiwei definitely can't marry him.
那采薇更不能嫁了呀
Just now, Prime Minister Zhang has brought up
方才张相又向我提起
again the re-election in the Ministries.
六部改选之事
[If Caiwei refuses to marry,]
若是三娘不嫁
then during the election,
这选官之时
I'll be assigned to guard the desert,
便会派我去大漠驻守
and our whole family will relocate there.
而且是举家搬迁
[Prime Minister Zhang is threatening Father]
张相竟然以
[on the pretext of exiling the whole family.]
全家发配大漠威胁爹爹
[My lord, my lady,]
老爷 夫人
[we have trouble!]
不好了
Caiwei... Caiwei ran off.
三姑娘 三姑娘跑了
It's said that
说是和一个
she eloped with a scholar
叫韩世元的书生
named Han Shiyuan.
私奔了
You ungrateful daughter!
逆女啊
My lord!
老爷
[-My lord!] -Father!
夫君 爹
-My lord.
老爷 夫君
Why are you all looking at me?
都看着我干吗呀
Did you find Caiwei?
三娘找着了
Then why aren't you looking for her now?
没找到还不赶紧去找去
[Even if you have to search every corner]
就算是翻遍襄安城
of Xiang'an, you must find that
也要把那个逆女
ungrateful daughter of mine!
给我找回来
Everyone, go look for her!
大家都给我找仔细了
Go, go, go. Go ahead now!
快快快去快去 快点
Wait.
等等
Keep it a secret.
保密
Don't let anyone know that
千万不能让人知道
Caiwei is missing.
三娘找不到了
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
对对对
Don't say that Caiwei has run away.
千万不能说三姑娘跑了
Just say that,
就说
you're looking for Xing's missing rabbit.
六姑娘养的兔子丢了
Yes.
是
Xing,
六娘
you're always out and about,
你平日在外走动得多
you know the area well.
比较熟悉
And you're close to Caiwei.
又和采薇交好
Go look for her as well.
便也一起出去找找吧
Sure.
好
Then, I'll go look for the rabbit too.
那我也去找兔子了啊
Yan Xing.
颜六娘
Are the daughters of your family
你们颜家庶女
not allowed to go home?
是不准回家吗
Why are you always wandering around outside?
怎么整日在外面游蹿
Chief Shen, please move aside.
大阁领请让开
My rabbit is missing.
我的兔子丢了
I'm looking for it.
我要去找
Is that so?
是吗
You lost your rabbit?
原来是兔子丢了呀
The Yan residence's gate
今天一整日
has been shut all day.
颜家大门一直紧闭
[I thought you were busy]
我还以为是在
[making preparations for the wedding.]
紧锣密鼓地准备新婚
Turns out you were looking for a rabbit.
原来是在关门找兔子
Chief Shen, if you're done mocking me,
大阁领若是嘲笑够了
I need to keep looking.
我就继续去找了
[You must find it then.]
那你可一定得找到啊
Tomorrow is my wedding
明日便是本阁领
with your sister.
与你三姐的大婚
[I really look forward]
到时候
to seeing you there
本阁领非常期待看到你
with your rabbit.
带着兔子一起来观礼
Chief Shen,
大阁领
please forgive my impudence.
颜幸冒昧
I need to ask you for a favor.
有一事相求
Ask me?
求我
Aside from the prisoners
除了牢里
in the dungeon who are desperate to die,
一心想死的囚犯
I doubt you could find anyone else
整个大苍
in the entire Da Cang who would
恐怕也找不出第二个人
ask me for a favor.
想要来求我办事了
Chief Shen, please break off the engagement.
求大阁领跟我三姐退婚
Do you know what you're talking about?
你知道自己在说什么吗
Yes.
知道
Please, Chief Shen,
求大阁领
break off the engagement with my sister.
取消跟我三姐的婚事
Although you hold no official position,
你虽然没有官职品阶
[you are at least a clerk]
但好歹也是个
[knowing how to read.]
识字的小吏
Do you know what
知不知道什么叫做
'Heaven's will cannot be defied' means?
天命不可违
Her Highness's words are absolute.
太皇太后金口玉言
Who am I to break it off.
哪儿来取消一说
Her Highness
太皇太后
holds Chief Shen in high regard,
对大阁领圣眷隆重
naturally she wishes to match you
自然是想给大阁领
with a suitable spouse.
配一段良缘
Right.
是啊
With Her Highness's careful selection
太皇太后精挑细选
and Prime Minister Zhang's endorsement,
又有张相作保
I believe your sister would
我相信与你三姐
surely be a good match to me.
一定是段良缘
It must be because Her Highness
那是太皇太后
doesn't truly know what the daughters
不知道我颜家女子
of the Yan family are like.
到底是什么样子
Considering my crude and disrespectful
您看我这么粗鄙无礼
manners, you should know that
就该知道
my sister would not be a
我三姐跟大阁领
good match for you, Chief Shen.
绝对不会是良配
You're saying that
你是说
your sister faked all her talents?
你三姐的才情都是假的
[Deceiving for fame like this is]
欺世盗名
essentially a crime against the emperor.
实乃欺君之罪
I...
我
I was talking about me.
我说的是我
You are indeed crude and disrespectful.
你确实粗鄙无礼
But I'm not marrying you.
但我娶的又不是你
[It's very unfortunate]
倒是你三姐
for your sister to have a sister
摊上你这么一个
like you.
无礼的庶妹
But you've never even met
可是你跟我三姐
my sister,
都没有见过
[aren't you afraid that]
你就不怕
you won't get along well
两情不相悦
and become estranged?
同床异梦终成怨偶
It doesn't matter.
那又何妨
How can it not matter?
那怎么会无妨呢
People should be with the one
人总是要跟相爱的人
they love.
在一起
Respect each other.
相敬如宾
Cherish each other.
彼此珍视
Only this way can you be happy.
这一辈子才能幸福啊
That's not important.
不重要
You...
你
You're truly hopeless.
你简直是无可救药
Can't talk sense to you!
不可理喻
The audacity!
放肆
Shen Du,
沈渡
even if I don't want to
就算我不愿意相信
believe the rumors,
外界的传言
but look at what you're like now,
可你看看你如今的样子
mean,
言语刻薄
eccentric,
行为乖张
ruthless
暴虐无道
and unreasonable.
蛮不讲理
Even if my sister
就算我三姐
has no one in her heart,
没有心仪之人
she still wouldn't marry you!
她又怎么会嫁给你呢
[Respect each other.]
相敬如宾
[Cherish each other.]
彼此珍视
These things
这些东西
are too far out of the reach for me now.
离我已经太远了
Mother,
母亲
someday,
总有一天
I will relocate you to the
我会把你迁到这世上
most noble and grand cemetery, where you
最高贵阔气的墓地
will receive endless tributes and honors.
享受万千祭拜
My lord,
主上
everything's ready.
一切都准备好了
Chief Shen,
大阁领
[Yan Xing’s]
虽然这颜家六娘
[words were very harsh,]
说话不中听
[but,]
但
[didn't you disagree]
您不也不想要
[this marriage either?]
这门婚事吗
Now that they want to break it off
既然咱们还没有吓唬
before we even scare them,
他们就要求退婚
why not turn their trick in your favor?
那您何不就顺水推舟
Of course I can't get married with her.
这婚当然不能结
But I
但这话
can't be the one that says this.
不能由我来说
Exactly.
对对对
[Her Highness granted you this marriage,]
太皇太后赐婚
[of course you have to accept it.]
大阁领自然是要领情
The Yans will have to be the ones
还是得让颜府
who break it off.
主动退婚才是
Our informant says,
据探子回报
Caiwei ran off with
这颜家三娘
that scholar,
与那书生私奔
[and they still haven't found her yet.]
至今还未找到
[Even if they don't break it off,]
就算不退婚
[tomorrow, we won't need to send the]
那明日的接亲
[bridal party to pick up the bride.]
也理所当然免了吧
[They are in the wrong.]
他们理亏
Prime Minister Zhang will naturally
太皇太后那边
have to find a way to smooth this over
张相自然得想办法
with Her Highness.
把这事给圆过去
That's a part of the story.
看戏怎么能只看一半呢
It's the Yans' problem
新娘在哪儿
where the bride is.
那是颜家的事
But of course
本阁领自然
I'll still send the bridal party
明早要派喜娘队伍
to pick up the bride tomorrow morning.
去接亲才是
You have all
各位
been with the Yan family for many years.
跟随我颜府多年
Now the Yan family is in such a crisis.
如今颜府遭此大劫
[Looks like heaven is determined to end us.]
怕是天要亡我颜家呀
I have prepared some silvers for all of you.
老夫备了些银两
[Go and find a new place for yourselves.]
各自寻找新的去处吧
I've already written my will.
这遗书我已经写好
Mother,
娘
I don't want to die, Mother.
我还不想死 娘
[-Mother.] -Fine.
娘 算了
I'll marry him.
我来嫁
[It's getting late.]
这都什么时辰了
[Why does the bride not show up?]
新娘子怎么还不出来
[We're missing the auspicious hour.]
要误了吉时了呀
Xing.
六娘
Xing, no, wait. Xing!
六娘 不行不行 六娘
I just don't think this is right.
我怎么想这事都不成
Think about
你想
who The White Death really is.
那白无常是什么人啊
He crawled out of the dead bodies
那是沈府
at Shen residence.
死人堆里爬出来的
What good can it do to you if you marry him.
你嫁过去能有好吗
Run away now.
赶紧跑
Take this.
这你拿着
You know people in the Ministry of Justice.
你在刑部认识的门路多
Just find some place
到时候找个地方
[to hide for three months.]
先躲三个月
[Wait for all this to blow over,]
等这段时期过了
[then you can come home.]
再回家
You don't need to worry about me.
你不用担心我
Your father bluffs like a paper tiger.
你爹他就是个纸老虎
[He won't prey on me.]
吃不了我
At most, I'll just
大不了啊
take really good care of him from now on.
我下半辈子精心伺候他
[I'll bring him tea, give him massages.]
端茶递水 捏肩捶腿
Worse comes to worst,
实在不行
you can just
你就一纸休书
divorce me.
把我给休了
I'll pick up my old job
我重操旧业
and sing operas.
唱戏
I can support you and me.
照样养活咱母女俩
Mom,
阿娘
which theater would take in
哪家园子
someone of your age.
还会收白发女伶啊
Although I'm the daughter of a concubine,
我虽然是庶女
I haven't faced any hardships
但从小在你们的庇护下
because of your care and protection.
并未受过什么委屈
Caiwei was especially good to me.
三姐更是对我极好
Back then,
当初
when I didn't want to study needlework and
我不愿意修习女红
was determined to be a female official,
一心想报考女官
it was Caiwei
是三姐
who knelt and begged all night
为我跪了一夜祠堂
for me.
求来的
You silly girl,
你这孩子
you only remember other people's good.
你就记得别人的好
I'm a part of the Yan family.
我是颜家的一份子
Of course I can't watch
自然不能
and do nothing at a moment like this.
看颜家受难而不管
Caiwei didn't want to marry him
三姐不愿意嫁
because she loves Han Shiyuan.
是因为她心中有韩郎君
But I have no one.
我心中又无牵挂
I'll just take her place.
便替她嫁好了
Foolish girl,
傻孩子
marriage is not that simple.
嫁人没那么简单
Mom,
阿娘
don't worry.
你别担心了
I have seen enough deaths in
六娘在刑部见过的死人
the Ministry of Justice.
多了去了
The White Death,
会会白无常
I can handle him.
也没有什么大不了的
Plus,
再说了
he's still made of flesh and blood.
他不过也是血肉之躯
What can he do to me
还真能把我
anyway?
勾到地府不成啊
[Okay, now.]
好了
Father,
父亲
Mother.
母亲
Please take care of my mom for me.
还请帮我照顾好我阿娘
I
女儿
bid you goodbye.
这便嫁了
[The bride is here.]
接新人
[Chief Shen,]
大阁领
[before the ceremony, the bride]
这拜堂之前
[and the groom can't see each other.]
新郎新娘不宜见面
[It brings bad luck stopping halfway.]
半路落轿更是不吉利
[And you the broom]
而且您这新郎官
[isn't even dressed up yet.]
怎么连喜服都没换呢
[Shut up.]
少废话
[The Imperial Guard is]
内卫府迎亲
picking up the bride, just do as we say.
就按照内卫府的规矩来
The Chief Shen will decide if it
吉不吉利
brings bad luck or not.
我们大阁领说了算
But...
这
My lady,
娘子
please allow me to see
为夫来看看
the face of this knowledgeable
博古通今
and virtuous
经明行修
noble lady of the Yan family.
名动襄安的颜家淑女
The so called noble lady
这位贤德淑女
is me.
就是我
Chief Shen, are you going to kill your wife
大阁领这是打算
in front of everyone?
当众杀妻吗
Don't forget this marriage
你别忘了
was granted by Her Highness.
这是太皇太后赐的婚事
[Although I don't hold an official rank]
虽然我现在没有品阶
[and am not a court-appointed official,]
不是朝廷命官
I'm still a clerk at the Ministry of Justice.
但起码也是刑部书吏
[This is not a crime scene,]
这不是办案现场
[nor is there any hostage situation.]
也没有嫌犯挟持
Even if you are the Chief Shen,
就算你是大阁领
you cannot just kill an innocent clerk
也不能不黑不白
without justification.
就将一个书吏无辜杀害
Is that so?
是吗
When did a fly can
什么时候
become a clerk?
一只苍蝇也能当书吏了
Chief Shen, there was no need to insult me.
大阁领何必如此羞辱我
Now that you hate this marriage
既然你对这桩婚事
so much,
这么不满
why not kill me now?
何不现在就杀了我
No rush.
别急
Even though today,
今日这把刀
this sword didn't touch you,
没砍到你脖子上
soon,
但很快
you'll wish you were dead.
就会让你求生无门
Xing is so bold
这颜六娘胆子真大
that she should marry for her sister.
竟敢替她三姐出嫁
This is a crime against the Emperor.
这可是欺君之罪
Her Highness only said
太皇太后只说
it is a daughter from the Yan family.
赐嫁颜家女
As for which daughter,
至于是几女
she couldn't care less.
太皇太后根本不在意
But you...
可是您
I don't care a bit.
我更不在乎了
I'll let her go anyway.
早晚是要赶走的
[There are not many interesting rabbits]
颜家也没有几只
[from the Yan family.]
有趣的兔子
The bolder one
还是胆子大的
is more interesting.
更有意思些
It's rare.
难得
She's not only bold,
她不仅胆子大
but actually quite smart.
似乎还挺有脑子的
Xing.
六娘
Chuichui.
垂垂
it's really you.
真的是你啊
[I heard]
我本来听说
[Caiwei was getting married today]
你三姐今日要嫁人
and was going to find you to
想去找你
watch the wedding together.
一起去凑热闹的
[But,]
结果
[as soon as I got there,]
一去颜府就看到
[I saw Madame Jin crying at the door,]
金姨娘在门口哭
saying that you're the one getting married.
说要嫁人的是你
[Xing,]
六娘
[do you not want to?]
你是不愿意吗
But, isn't the groom
可是这新郎官
Shen Du?
不是沈渡吗
He's not Shen Du anymore.
他已经不是沈渡了
He's the ruthless The White Death now.
而是暴虐无道的白无常
Chuichui, don't worry.
垂垂你放心
Go back now.
你先回去吧
No.
不行
How can I just watch you
我怎么能眼睁睁看着你
falling into the hands of The White Death?
落入白无常手里呢
[I'll go with you,]
我陪你去
[even if]
这虎穴
it is a trap.
姐妹陪你蹚了
Something's wrong.
坏了坏了
What's wrong.
什么坏了
Clam down. Tell me.
别着急 慢慢说
The bride actually came!
新娘子居然来了
The bride?
新娘子
What kind of rules do they have here?
什么家规特殊啊
The Shen residence
这沈府弄得
looks like a mourning hall.
跟个灵堂似的
This doesn't look like a wedding at all.
哪有半点婚礼的样子
[And what's with all the white lanterns?]
这么多白灯笼
My lady,
夫人
you just got here.
您初到沈府
The servants surely dare not be negligent.
府内下人万万不敢怠慢
Marriage requires
这婚姻之事嘛
the right timing, place, and harmony.
讲究是天时地利人和
A fortune teller
头些日子
studied the birth date and time
请大师算过
a few days ago.
您二人的八字
That's why it's not suitable to
所以今日府内
have festive decorations today.
不宜张灯结彩
No problem.
无妨
You decide, butler.
沈管家定夺便是
This way, please.
请
The main room of the residence
大阁领中屋
is not suitable as a bridal chamber
因为常年独居
because it has been vacant
缺少祥和之气
and lacks a certain harmonious energy,
不宜作婚房
which could invite misfortune.
容易引起血光之灾
A new room has been arranged for you.
特意给夫人备了新房
[Please get some rest and wait for]
您早点歇息
Chief Shen to return from his prayers.
且等大阁领祭祷回来
Don't take things too far.
你们不要欺人太甚了
It's okay.
没事
Please, lead the way.
烦请带路
Please.
请
Butler Shen,
沈管家
do you still recall
不知道您可记得
my birth date and time?
我的生辰八字是什么
Er...
这
It's not appropriate to
女儿家的八字
publicly disclose
自然是不好
a woman's birth details.
当众说出口的
Thank you for being so considerate.
多谢管家细心
Please.
请
[Chuichui,]
垂垂
have some preserved fruit.
吃个蜜饯
How are you in the mood to eat?
你还有心情吃
My lady,
夫人
may you soon be blessed with a child.
祝您和郎君早生贵子
You're doing that now?
现撒
Did you think Xing
你们是不是压根
would never come and marry?
就没想过六娘会嫁进门
Chuichui,
垂垂
don't be too harsh on them.
别为难她们了
They are truly over the line.
他们这也太过分了
They probably thought I would've
怕是都以为
run away halfway.
我会半路跑路吧
But this is simply
那可是这也
not acceptable.
太欺负人了吧
It's nothing.
这有什么
Just formalities.
虚礼而已
Formalities?
虚礼
But your dowry comes too easy.
那你们家实礼也亏了呀
I heard
我听说
all the gifts Shen Du sent to
沈渡送到你们家的
your family were rubbish,
全是那些样子货
not one decent thing among them.
没有一件正经东西
You...
这
may as well
这还不如
marry into an ordinary family.
嫁给一个寻常人家算了
Al least they would welcome you
起码还实在
with the best things they can give.
人家迎亲都是双飞大雁
But all you got is a chicken.
你家就送只大母鸡
How can you still laugh?
你还笑得出来
If he doesn't want to marry me,
他既然不想娶
I'd rather insist on marrying him.
那我还偏要嫁
Chief Shen,
大阁领 不好了
news from the imperial guards says that
前方内卫来消息了
that bride is truly unusual.
那新娘子简直邪了门了
Not only did she not run away,
她不但没走
but she actually came back.
反倒又回来了
She should be at the Shen residence now.
这会儿应该已经在沈府了
Yan Xing is truly something.
果然是颜六娘
But most importantly,
关键是
no one thought this wedding
大伙压根就没有觉得
would happen.
这婚礼能成
So they didn't prepare anything.
什么都没有准备
And she
她倒好
not only joins the decoration,
不仅一起到现场去布置
she's actually giving ideas
这会儿还在那儿
herself!
给人出主意呢
Let her.
随她
There have been many women
往年那些不怕死的
who have risked everything to
想缠您嫁入沈府的
marry into the Shen residence,
的确不少
but as soon as you use
可您只要略微用
a little bit of tactics,
那么一点手段
they would run away scared.
马上屁滚尿流地跑了
No one dared to go in the bridal chamber
哪有见过您的刀
after seeing your sword.
还敢进洞房的
After she arrived,
进府以后
Butler Shen deliberately withheld
沈管家刻意扣了
her dowry.
她的聘礼
She was not angry but insisted on marrying you.
她不但不生气还是要嫁
This woman is well-trained,
这女子训练有素
[and is not afraid of hardships.]
迎难而上
Prime Minister Zhang must have sent her
张相派她来
as part of a grand scheme.
绝对是个大阴谋
If even you can tell,
你都看得出来
what kind of scheme is that?
还算是什么阴谋
This rabbit
这次这个兔子
is truly much more interesting
比起以往那些
than the ones before.
还真是有意思得多
And the matchmaking official...
官媒那边
Chief Shen, don't worry.
大阁领放心
I've already instructed
属下已经给接亲队那边
the bridal party.
都敲打过了
By now everyone would assume that
现在大家只会认为您是
the wedding went well,
娶亲顺遂
and everything has settled.
婚礼已成
Now I know
我算是知道
why they call Shen Du the White Death.
沈渡为什么叫白无常了
Look at all these rooms.
你看这一个个的
They looked like mourning halls during
白日里就像个灵堂
the day, and now at night,
到了晚上
it's still as bright as day.
还是这么亮如白昼的
Are they trying to light up the way
难不成是要照亮地府
for the ghosts from hell?
给鬼魅引路不成
[Maybe it's because he became wicked these years,]
怕是他这些年黑了心
[and he fears ghosts might come at night.]
怕夜半鬼叫门吧
Xing,
六娘
do you
你现在
really have no feelings left
对白无常
for White Death?
真的只有厌烦了
I was so blind when I was young
是我年少时瞎了眼
and actually thought he was a decent man.
以为他是个好儿郎
After these two days,
经过这两日
I finally saw him through.
我算是看透了
And what he said when he stopped the sedan chair...
那他拦轿时说的那些话
He just didn't want me to come here
他应该是不想我进府
and was trying to scare me away.
要是能吓就吓走了
Then what are you going to do?
那你可怎么办啊
Don't worry.
别担心
This marriage was granted
毕竟也是
by Her Highness herself.
太皇太后亲赐的婚事
He wouldn't harm me
他也不会一时三刻
anytime soon.
向我动手的
I'll be very careful.
我小心谨慎一些
One day at a time.
挨得一日算一日
At least I'll have to hold on
怎么着也要熬到
until after the re-elections,
朝中定了外调的人选
so my family
让我家
wouldn't be sent to the desert.
不至于被发配荒漠
You didn't get married,
你这哪是结婚啊
you fell into a monster's nest.
你这分明就是进了魔窟
Survival in a dire situation
地府中求生
surely wouldn't be easy.
哪有那么容易啊
It's getting late.
天色也不早了
You should go back now.
你快回去吧
Your father would be worried.
你爹该着急了
I'm not going.
我不走
I'll stay here with you.
我要留在这儿陪你
You don't come to me every day, do you?
那你还能每天都来陪我
Are you going to marry into this place too?
难不成再搭上一个
Don't worry.
你放心吧
Tonight,
他今晚
he will definitely act
定是会摆出一副
all cold and annoyed to me.
冷落嫌弃我的姿态
He wouldn't come in my room.
不会进我那厢房的
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
This is the Shen residence.
这里是沈府
This is my wedding night.
今夜是我大婚
Why can't I come here?
我为何不能来
As for you,
倒是你
they say the daughter of the Yan family
颜氏有女
possesses poetic talent,
咏絮之才
is skilled in calligraphy and dance,
笔歌墨舞
good in scholarship,
经明行修
knowledgeable,
博古通今
known for her virtue and grace,
其贤德淑女之名
and her reputation unparalleled in Xiang'an.
冠绝襄安
Which of these descriptions
这些修辞
fits you?
哪个与你相配
Great fit.
配
Of course, it was Her Highness who believed
当然是太皇太后
I, Yan Xing, would be a
觉得我颜六娘
great fit for you.
同你沈大阁领极为相配
Or why would she grant this marriage?
不然怎么会赐婚呢
Chief Shen, if you're not
大阁领你要是
content with me,
对我不满意的话
just divorce me.
休了我便是
My lady, your thoughts
夫人脑袋里的想法
are as fanciful
倒是与你的脸蛋一样
as your face is pretty.
想得太美了
With such a beautiful bride,
如此俊俏的美娇娘
I should only be so happy,
我爱不释手才是
how could I ever consider divorcing her?
怎么会轻易休了呢
I've never seen a bride who runs around
还从未见过礼未成
the courtyard before the wedding is over.
满院子乱跑的新娘
If you don't want to end up with
你若是不想一个不小心
a broken leg or
在沈府断了腿
a missing arm here at the Shen residence,
或是少个胳膊
then you'll need to behave yourself.
便记得规矩些
My lord, you're right.
夫君说得对
My lord,
夫君啊
since Her Highness had said so,
我既然领了圣意
then I'll fulfill my responsibilities
那就自然要做好
as the Lady of the Shen residence
大阁领府的沈夫人
and take really good care
将您伺候得
of you.
妥妥帖帖的
This is how you
就凭这个
want to seduce me?
也想挑逗我
Since you said you would take care of me,
既然说要好好侍奉我
then let me tell you three things.
那我便告诉你三件事
First,
第一
don't even dream about
不要妄想成为
becoming the real Lady Shen.
真正的沈夫人
It's only an act
我与你之间
between us.
有名无实
Second,
第二
don't expect to get any
不要妄想从我这里
information from me.
得到任何情报
I know what Prime Minister Zhang
我知道张相派你来
sent you here for.
是什么目的
Third,
第三
you're not the wife
不是我沈渡
that I willingly chose.
心甘情愿娶的妻子
Don't even think about surviving here.
别妄想在沈府活下去
Lord,
郎君
did you see Lady Shen?
见着夫人了
And the wedding ceremony...
那拜堂成亲之事
Just think of it as if it's done.
就算是拜过了
Then,
那
about the West Chamber...
西厢房那边
Let her stay there.
就让她待着吧
[Chief Shen.]
大阁领
There was a fire at Ming Hall.
明堂失火了
How did the fire start?
明堂因何失火
Someone burned himself
有人在明堂自焚
and started the fire.
结果引发了火灾
The one who started it
自焚之人
has been burned beyond recognition.
已烧得面目模糊
Deploy more guards right away
立刻加派人手
to secure the palace.
确保皇宫护卫
Find out the identity of the suicide.
查清楚自焚者的身份
And don't miss anything.
不准有任何遗漏
Yes.
是
[Why can't I see her?]
为什么不让我们见
[I work at the Ministry of Justice.]
我是刑部女官
[I went in there]
就昨天
[with your Lady]
还陪你家夫人
[only yesterday.]
进了新房的
[You really can't go in, lady.]
你真进不去 姑娘
[Without the butler's permission,]
没有管家的吩咐
[Please.]
拜托了
[we really can't let you in.]
我们不能让您进去
[Yeah.]
是啊
Chuichui.
垂垂
You can't go in.
不能进
Xing,
六娘
something happened!
出大事了
-Madame.
夫人 夫人
A pair of bodies were found
在西明寺竹林
near the bamboo grove of Ximing Temple
附近发现了一对尸体
and their condition is very suspicious.
尸状极为蹊跷
The Ministry of Justice and Inspectors
刑部和异良人
have already sent people there.
已经派人去了
Let's go.
走